Guide to the Manchester Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Albums, 1697/98 Feb 8; Series I
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, respecting a proposed pardon and pension to some one (described here as la personne, and in other letters as "la personne dont il s'agit") for the discovery of important facts, and giving instructions on other subjects. (Partly in cipher, deciphered. Printed, as deciphered, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 104) Whitehall, 1699/1700 Feb 15 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Matthew Prior to the E of M, announcing the conclusion of the "grand affair," and mentioning the address of the Commons to the King, "la personne dont il s'agit," etc. (Printed. Cole's memoirs, p. 106) Whitehall, 1699/1700 Feb 22 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Mr. Lubières to the E of M, requesting the Earl to bring to the notice of M. de Torcy certain difficulties respecting French servants at Orange. (In French. A translation is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 105) Orange, 1700 Mar 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Copy of Treaty between the Kings of France and Great Britain, and the States General, for the partition of the Spanish dominions after the death of the reigning King of Spain. (In French. p. 12) London, 1700 Mar 3 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Abstract of the same Treaty as signed at London, 21 February, 1699 (o.s.), and at the Hague, 25 March, 1700 (n.s.) (In French. A translation is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 113) London and the Hague, 1700 Mar 25 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - A long and unsigned document on the proposed partition of the Spanish dominions, and its probable consequences. (In Italian. Partly in cipher, deciphered. p. 5), 1700 Mar 7 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - R. Yard to the E of M, referring to the unpopularity of the King, through his partiality for the Dutch, and giving an account of business in Parliament, including the Bill for the Union. Whitehall, 1699/1700 Mar 7 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, on the outbreak of hostilities in Livonia. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 107) Hamburg, 1699/1700 Feb 29/ (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Don Silvio Boccone, Cistercian monk, to the E of M ("Duca de M"), asking the Earl to distribute copies of a work written by the monk. (In Italian) Palermo, 1700 Mar 12 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, chiefly on the subject of an alleged plot to murder the King. (Partly in cipher, deciphered. Printed, as deciphered, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 110) Whitehall, 1699/1700 Mar 14 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The King of Sweden to the King of France, on an infraction of the treaty of Oliva. (Latin. Another copy of the same document has already been described, No. 683, Vol. II of the "Manchester Correspondence," iii.), 1700 Mar 14 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, on the proceedings of the King of Poland against the Swedes, and announcing that the King of England had fitted out a squadron to preserve the peace. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 111) Whitehall, 1699/1700 Mar 18 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, expressing an opinion that affairs in the North depended entirely on the appearance of the English and Dutch flags. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 115) Hamburg, 1699/1700 Mar 22/ (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Secret Article of the Second Treaty of Partition. (In French. A translation is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 119) London and the Hague, 1700 Mar 25 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - R. Yard to the E of M, giving an account of proceedings in Parliament. Whitehall, 1700 Mar 28 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, instructing the latter to represent to the French Court the dangers of war in the North, and touching upon the subjects of the alleged plot, and the Danzig ships. (Partly in cipher, deciphered. Printed, as deciphered, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 117) Whitehall, 1700 Apr 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - [Matthew Prior] (whose signature is omitted) to the E of M, asking for the Earl's good offices in the presentation to the library of the King of France of a Horace printed at Cambridge, and in a contemplated purchase of Greek types. (Printed, not quite correctly, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 118) Whitehall, 1700 Apr 1 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, on the recall of Mr. Stanyan, and the expenses of the Embassy. Whitehall, 1700 Apr 4 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Matthew Prior to the E of M, on parliamentary business, etc. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 121) Whitehall, 1700 Apr 10 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Matthew Prior to the E of M, on parliamentary business, the prospects of parties, etc. (Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 122) Whitehall, 1700 Apr 11 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - M. Van Vryberge to the E of M, recommending the case of the Sieur de Rodon, one of the King's officers and a native of Orange, and mentioning enclosure of his memorial. The journey [of William III] to Holland was not, and probably would not be, spoken of until the proceedings of the Scotch Parliament were known. (In French) London, 1700 Apr 15/26 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, instructing the latter to renew his representations at the French Court with regard to the necessity of preserving the peace in the North, and announcing that "the great affair was quite finished," etc. (Partly in cipher. Printed, without the part in cipher, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 122) Whitehall, 1700 Apr 15 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Matthew Prior to the E of M, on the presentation of the Cambridge Horace, on the desire of the University of Cambridge to be furnished with Greek types from France, on the recall of Mr. Stanyan, etc. (Printed, in part only, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 124) Whitehall, 1700 Apr 18 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, instructing the latter to act in concert with M. de Torcy respecting the notification of "the affair" at Vienna and Madrid, etc. (Partly in cipher, deciphered. Printed, as deciphered, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 124) Whitehall, 1700 Apr 18 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Matthew Prior to the E of M, expressing "My Lord's" [the Earl of Jersey's] regret at not having yet had an opportunity of speaking to the King "to be" the E of M's "gossip.", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, giving instructions on various matters, and mentioning the alleged plot. (Partly in cipher, deciphered. Printed, as deciphered, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 126) Hampton Court, 1700 Apr 25 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - H. Greg to the E of M, touching the goods of English subjects seized on the Danzig ships, and mentioning enclosures. (Printed, almost entire, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 123) Copenhagen, 1700 Apr 27/16 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Matthew Prior to the E of M, referring to the "great affair," Sir William Ellis, Lord Chief Justice Holt, etc. (Partly in cipher. Deciphered and printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 128) Hampton Court, 1700 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - J. Robinson to Mr. Stanyan, giving an account of military and naval movements. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 128) Stockholm, 1700 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, to the effect that whatever was undertaken by Danes or Saxons was concerted at Berlin. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 125) Berlin, 1700 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, conveying the King's approval of the E of M's past proceedings in his Embassy, and giving instructions on various points to guide his future conduct. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 131) Whitehall, 1700 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - The E of M to Mr. Stanhope (then at the Hague), on the complications in the North, and asking for information with respect to the intentions of the Muscovites, which were considered of great importance. At the top is a note by the Earl: "This should come before the letter to the Earl of Jersey, dated, Paris, May 8, 1700." (Draft) Paris, 1700 May 7 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - On the same paper is a draft of a letter from the E of M to Mr. Cressett, on the same subject, with mention of a report that the Muscovites intended to assist the King of Poland. Paris, 1700 May 7 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - J. Robinson to Mr. Stanyan, giving an account of military and naval movements in the North, and stating that the Czar would probably not interfere. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 134) Stockholm, 1700 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, stating that there was much ill will against the King of England at Berlin, and expressing a wish to be recalled. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 128) Berlin, 1700 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, respecting the interpretation of an article in the Treaty of Partition in certain eventualities. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 135) Hampton Court, 1700 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Alexander Stanhope to the E of M, expressing hopes that the King of Denmark would be brought to agree to a reasonable peace, and that neither the King of France nor the Czar had hostile intentions. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs p. 129) The Hague, 1700 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, stating that all he could obtain from the Court of Berlin (which he was leaving) was a very doubtful neutrality, and giving an account of some movements in the North. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 133) Berlin, 1700 May 18 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, informing him that the Elector of Brandenburg had been making overtures "underhand" to France, in favour of Denmark and Poland, and instructing him how to proceed. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 138) Hampton Court, 1700 May 20 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, giving instructions on various subjects. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 139) Hampton Court, 1700 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, describing the approach of the Swedes and Lunenburghers, and expressing a belief that the Danes would soon change their tone. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 137) Hamburg, 1700 May 31 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, giving an account, at some length, of conversations with M. de Torcy and others, at Paris, on the subject of affairs in the North, and other matters, and expressing confidence in the good faith of the French Court. (Draft, p. 6. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 141) Paris, 1700 Jun 9 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Alexander Stanhope to the E of M, expressing delight at the probable "agony" of the Pope and the Spaniards when the Partition Treaty was made known to them, and giving some particulars on the state of affairs in the North. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 140) The Hague, 1700 Jun 3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - M. Plantamour to the E of M, on affairs in the North, and especially on the movements of the Elector of Hanover, and the Duke of Zell, and the probable relief of Toninghen by the Lunenburghers. (In French. A translation is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 140) Berlin, 1700 Jun 6 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, on affairs in the North, with especial reference to the refusal of French mediation by the Duke of Holstein. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 142) Hamburg, 1700 Jun 11 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, chiefly on the state of affairs in the North. (Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 143) Paris, 1700 Jun 12 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - M. Plantamour to the E of M, announcing that orders had been given for the march of troops to the Elbe, etc. (In French. A translation, however not quite complete, is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 144) Berlin, 1700 Jun 13 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Project for an Armistice of fifteen days between the King of Denmark and the Guarantor of the Treaty of Altona. (In French) Pinnenberg, 1700 Jun 13 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, to the effect that neither Denmark or Holstein was willing to accept the mediation of France apart from that of the Emperor, and that an engagement between the Danes and the Allies appeared imminent. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 144) Hamburg, 1700 Jun 14 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Paul Methuen to Mr. Stanyan, giving an account of the reception of the news of the Partition Treaty by the King of Portugal. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 144) Lisbon, 1700 Jun 15 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, on the mode of communicating the Treaty to the minor German Courts, and other matters. (Draft. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 145) Paris, 1700 Jun 16 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Robert Sutton to [the E of M], expressing an opinion that the Emperor, though displeased with the Partition Treaty, had not yet formed any resolution upon it. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 146) Vienna (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, suggesting the expediencey of apprehending certain persons, and giving some particulars of Northern affairs. (Draft. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 146) Paris, 1700 Jun 19 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Earl of Jersey to the E of M, on the conditions upon which the Emperor and Portugal would "come to" the Partition Treaty, and giving instructions on various matters. Hampton Court, 1700 Jun 20 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, on Northern politics. (Printed, not quite correctly, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 147) Pinnenberg, 1700 Jun 21 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, on the affairs of the Prince de Montbeliard, the doings at St. Germain's, etc. (Draft. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 147) Paris, 1700 Jun 23 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - M. Lubières to the E of M, requesting the good offices of the latter with M. de Torcy in the case of M. de Rodon (against whom there had been some misrepresentations made by his enemies, as well as on behalf of "le nommé François Vial," who had been detained three months in prison, and had been a resident in Orange since 1665. (In French) Orange, 1700 Jun 24 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Alexander Stanhope to the E of M, on the communication of the Partition Treaty to the Powers, and on the policy of the Czar. (Printed. Cole'd Memoirs, p. 148) The Hague, 1700 Jun 24 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - R. Yard to the E of M, announcing that the Earl of Jersey had succeeded the Duke of Shrewsbury as Lord Chamberlain, etc. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 155) Whitehall, 1700 Jun 24 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, on the mode of reception of the Treaty of Partition by the various Powers, on affairs in the North, on the case of the Prince de Montbeliard, etc. (Draft, 7 pages. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 149) Paris, 1700 Jun 26 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - M. Plantamour to the E of M, announcing a change of policy at the Court of Berlin, which had withdrawn its support from Denmark, and recommended that Power come to terms. (In French. A translation is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 151) Berlin, 1700 Jun 27 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, complaining of the partiality of the French Ambassador towards Denmark, and giving an account of the state of affairs in the North. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 152) Pinnenberg, 1700 Jun 28 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The E of M to Mr. Prior, promising to let the Earl of Jersey know, by a subsequent letter, what was occurring. (Draft. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 152) Paris, 1700 Jun 30 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, on the case of the Prince de Montbeliard, on Venetian affairs, on the publication of the Treaty of Partition, etc. (Draft. Incomplete. For conclusion see 30. Printed, with some variations, under date July 8th, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 156) Paris, 1700 Jul 1/4 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Alexander Stanhope to the E of M, on the state of affairs in the North. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 153) The Hague, 1700 Jul 1 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, giving an extract from a despatch on Northern affairs and policy, which had been sent to Mr. Vernon. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 153) Hamburg, 1700 Jul 2 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, mentioning an enclosure relating to news brought by recent letters from Spain. (Draft) Paris, 1700 Jul 3 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Also, on the same sheet of paper, draft of letter from the E of M to Mr. Prior, stating tha "Col. Slinsby" had gone to England, possibly with the consent of the Government. Paris, 1700 Jul 3 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, on the Emperor and the Treaty of Partition, affairs in the North, the cases of M. de Rodon and the Prince de Montbeliard, etc. (Draft. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 156) Paris, 1700 Jul 7 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - J. Robinson to the E of M, giving copy of letter of same date to "Mr. Secretary [Vernon], on affairs in the North, especially the movements of the fleets. (Printed, Cole's Memoirs, p. 164) Malmöe, 1700 Jul 7 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey. (Part of a draft asking for employment for Mr. Stanyan. It seems to be the conclusion of 23), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - James Vernon to the E of M, on the case of the ship "William and Jane," seized by the French on the coast of Africa, on the state of affairs in the North of Europe, and on the Scottish Parliament. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 168) Whitehall, 1700 Jul 8 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, forwarding particulars (as sent to Mr. Secretary Vernon) relating to the affairs in the North. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 157) Hamburg, 1700 Jul 9 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Copy of Memorial presented by the French Ambassador to the Diet at Bâle, announcing the conclusion of the Partition Treaty. (In French) Bâle, 1700 Jul 9 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - The E of M to Mr. Prior, regretting that the Earl of Jersey and Mr. Prior had left their offices. (Draft. Printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 159) Paris, 1700 Jul 10 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Undirected and unsigned letter, beginning "Sir," giving some particulars of affairs in the North, and indicating the reserve of the Court of Vienna on the subject of the Partition Treaty. (Printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 160, as part of a despatch of the same date from Mr. Sutton, in whose handwriting it appears to be, to the E of M. See 44.) Vienna, 1700 Jul 10 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey. (Draft on the end of letter 38. See below.) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - James Vernon to the E of M, asking for information repecting the movements of "the assassins," etc. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 173) Whitehall, 1700 Jul 15 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, mentioning enclosure from Mr. Cressett, giving some account of the proposed mediation in the North, and the probable reception of the Partition Treaty by the Swiss, etc. (Draft, imperfect. See 36. The whole letter is printed, with some variations, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 162.) Paris, 1700 Jul 17 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - M. Hervart to the E of M, on the approaching Diet at Soleure and the reception of the Partition Treaty by the Swiss. (In French. A translation, under the date 7/18 July, is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 164.) Berne [Bern], 1700 Jul 8/18 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - James Vernon to the E of M, on the seizure of English ships by the French, off the coast of Africa, the slave trade, and other matters affecting mercantile marine, etc. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 174) Whitehall, 1700 Jul 18 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, announcing that the Danes had at length consented to treat, and giving some particulars of affairs in the North. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 174) Whitehall, 1700 Jul 19 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Copy of a statement (unsigned, but for which Mr. Robinson was probably responsible), giving an account of the movements of the Swedish fleet, the protests of Admiral Guldenlew, and interviews with him, etc. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 165) Allies' camp, near Oldeslo, 1700 Jul 19 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Copy of an address to the "Gran Duca" [of Tuscany?], announcing the conclusion of the Partition Treaty. (In Italian. A translation is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 178. where the document is described as "Sir Lambert Blackwell's Speech.") (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - R. Sutton to the E of M, mentioning enclosed advices, and expressing an opinion that the Emperor would give his good offices towards securing peace in the north, and would not take active measures to prevent the execution of the Partition Treaty. (Printed, under date July 10, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 160. See 35) Vienna, 1700 Jul 20 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - The E of M to the Earl of Jersey, mentioning an enclosure, and the acceptance of mediation by King of Denmark. (Copy) Paris, 1700 Jul 21 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Extract from a letter from M. le Comte de Chamilly to some unnamed person at Hamburg, mentioning a promise of a favourable answer from the King of Denmark, but expressing doubts on the subject. The letter was to be communicated to the Abbé Bidal., 1700 Jul 22 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Alexander Stanhope to the E of M, referring to an enclosed abstract of letter from Mr. Robinson, and making some remarks on Northern affairs. (Printed, not quite correctly, in Cole's Memoirs, p. 169) The Hague, 1700 Jul 22 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Abraham Stanyan to the E of M, on the subject of Broccard's salary, and announcing that Mr. Montagu would write to him by Lord Kingston, whom "several knights and Kitt Catters" attended to his yacht. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 181) London, 1700 Jul 22/Aug 2 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - R. Yard to the E of M, on the Darien capitulation and the state of feeling in Scotland. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 181) Whitehall, 1700 Jul 22 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Cavaliere Coriolano Montemagni to the English Envoy [Sir Lambert Blackwell], sending (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - the reply of the Grand Duke of Tuscany to the communication in which he was made acquainted with the Partition Treaty. (Copies. In Italian. Translations are printed in Cole's Memoirs, pp. 177-8), 1700 Jul 23 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Copy of the reply of the Grand Duke of Tuscany to the French Envoy on the subject of the Partition Treaty. (In Italian. A translation is printed in Cole's Memoirs, p. 178) (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Sir Lambert Blackwell to the E of M, mentioning enclosure of his speech to the Grand Duke, and expressing an expectation of obtaining a more definite answer than he had yet received on the subject of the Partition Treaty. Florence, 1700 Jul 23 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, on the state of affairs in the North, and mentioning enclosure of of a copy of a letter from M. de Chamilli. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 170) Hamburg, 1700 Jul 23 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - James Vernon to the E of M, on the English ships seized by the French off the coast of Guinea, and the claims of the African Company, and on the correspondence and agents passing between Scotland and St. Germain. (Partly in cipher, deciphered) Whitehall, 1700 Jul 25 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - William Blathwayt to the E of M, on the Danish difficulty, and mentioning enclosure relating to the position of the fleets. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 178) The Hague, 1700 Jul 16/27 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Alexander Stanhope to the E of M, on the retreat of the Danish Fleet, the defeat of the Saxons, etc, with mention of enclosure. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 176) The Hague, 1700 Jul 29 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - James Cressett to the E of M, on politics in the North, and mentioning the bombardment of Copenhagen by Sir George Rooke. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 178) Hamburg, 1700 Jul 30 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Sir Lambert Blackwell to the E of M, mentioning enclosures already described, under date July 23, viz., answers of the Grand Duke of Tuscany to the English and French Envoys on the subject of the Partition Treaty. (Printed. Cole's Memoirs, p. 177) Florence, 1700 Jul 30 (Box 4, Folder 59)